Akshay Siddhpura

Applications Developer-2 (Oracle India)

Gandhinagar | +91-9099063892 | adsiddhpura@hotmail.com



Profile

Full stack developer with 4.8 years of thorough experience in designing and implementing software application and frameworks with a talent of solving problems analytically, well versed in managing team members and also to be a team player to ensure timely completion of all deadlines.

Professional Experience

Oracle India Pvt. Ltd.

Oct 2017 - Present

Human Capital Management - Fusion Applications Developer

Oracle Fusion Applications are enterprise resource planning software applications from Oracle Corporation. It is distributed across various product families; including financial management, human capital management, customer relationship management, supply chain management. Oracle Fusion Human Capital Management is a complete suite of HR products that offers the complete spectrum of HR functions like person management, employment management, payroll, absences, work-structures, etc. integrated together in a seamless manner.

- Implemented various task flows of Person module functionalities using JAVA/ADF
- Spearheaded integration project of Address component and make component easily customizable for other teams and products.
- Redesign and implemented Person Module for mobile compatibility and integrated task flow in Java/ADF
- Improving existing functionality in the module in terms of high coherence and loose coupling.
- Interacting with customers to reiterate over the accessibility of application and efficiently enhances the user experience.

Tata Consultancy Services, India

Jun 2014 - Oct 2017

Commercial Taxation System - Module lead

- A key member of Framework Team for Taxation Projects and Module Lead for Payment & Registration modules for one of the Taxation Projects.
 - Performed Third-party integration with 10 banks.
 - Worked with framework team to develop various components of TCS's taxation framework on technologies like J2EE, Spring, Hibernate.
- Lead for the customized Dashboard framework, its architecture depended on Materialized Views in Enterprise DB and custom components developed with SQL DB interaction using JSON (mainly for Personalized User Profiles).
 - Reports were custom generated from a stored procedure or Materialized View.
 - Rendered reports were configured in terms of columns, parameters and various filters after customization of Data Tables.
 - Implemented Configurable multi data source structure for Near site and Far Site database
 that uses the transnational database for login and audit purpose and relied on
 on far site databases for heavy procedures and queries.
- Customized Bootstrap Framework as per the needs of Taxation Projects
 - Implemented configurations to change Bootstrap Themes (UI elements, Component and their Responsiveness) as per the requirement

Personal passions

Apparel Recommendation Engine

- A recommendation engine which recommends similar apparel products in e-commerce using product descriptions and Images.
- The recommendation engine uses information about 1,80,000 Amazon products.
- The project includes Exploratory data analysis and finding similar apparel.

Area of Expertise

- Programming: Java, J2EE, Python.
- Frameworks: ADF, Hibernate, Spring.
- Web: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, JSON, REST API, Bootstrap-css
- Tools: Eclipse, Jdeveloper, Tortoise SVN, Jupyter Notebook, ADE.
- Other: Apache Tomcat, JBoss, WebLogic.

Certifications

- Python For Data Science March 2018 -by IBM
- Workshop of Apparel Recommendation Engine for Amazon clothing.
- Atteneded training for Application Development Framework
- Conducted technical training of Dashboard framework and Bootstrap framework across TCS Govt.ISU.

Achievements

- "Best Practice Award" across TCS
 India for development of Dashboard
 Framework
- Awarded as "ILP Kudos" during corporate & technical training at TCS.
- Winner of Codejam competition at the Techfest of DDU University.

Education

 Bachelor of Technology in Computer Engineering

Dharmsinh Desai University, Gujarat, India 74% **2010 - 2014**

Languages

English, Hindi, Gujarati